Reid Watson

Brooklyn, NY 11237 | 206-914-8755 | j.watsonreid@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer specializing in Ruby, Javascript, and React/Redux. I am a recent graduate of Flatiron School's Software Engineering Bootcamp. I have previous experience as a professional actor, performing in numerous venues throughout New York City. I strive to utilize the communication skills, emotional intelligence, and collaborative energy that acting has given me to be an effective member of a development team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Active Record, SQLite/Postgres, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap/Semantic UI, React and Redux, Git, Heroku, WordPress

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Ascent - Github | Demo

A rock climbing exploration website, where users can search for, favorite, and learn about a vast number of rock climbing sites throughout the United States

- Developed with Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Javascript and React/Redux
- Created dynamic search forms and information cards for each climb
- Implemented an interactive map feature, using the Google Maps API to mark and display climbing areas

BlackJack.JS - Github | Demo

A fun, engaging digital blackjack game with card animations and gameplay statistics tracking

- Implemented game logic for hitting, staying, busting over 21, automated dealer hit below 17, and variable Ace card value
- Created custom CSS animations for the playing cards
- Used the DeckOfCards API to generate random decks/cards
- Built a Rails server side to persist user data and track player performance

BackLog - Github | Demo

A video game cataloging app used to search for, like, and review various video games and console systems

- Seeded rails backend with data from the RAWG video game API
- Built the app entirely using Rails
- Implemented server models, data relationships, controllers and view pages, as well as Auth via BCrypt

EXPERIENCE

Professional Actor

06/2017 - 09/2020

- Performing in over 20 productions in regional and Off-Broadway theaters throughout the Pacific Northwest, as well as New York
- Leading roles at companies such as Hamlet Isn't Dead, The Evening Crane Theatre, Island Shakespeare Festival and ACT
- Specializing in Shakespeare, and using over 6 years of training in voice, speech, and diction to clearly communicate complex, poetic language to an audience

Gibney Dance Company

New York, NY

Lighting & Sound Technician

02/2019 - 04/2020

- Working in a fast-paced, high pressure environment, installing lighting instruments, running sound equipment, and stage managing for over 30 dance productions
- Fulfilling specific performance needs for top NYC choreographers
- Working backstage during performances, managing an inventory of hundreds of pieces of equipment, including light and sound boards, speakers, and microphones

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

09/2020 - 12/2020

Whitman College

Walla Walla, WA

Bachelor of Arts

Biophysics, Biochemistry, and Molecular Biology (Combined Degree Program)

05/2017